<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modDesc descVersion="110">
    <author>SimGamerJen, Hyper138</author>
    <version>2.0.1.9</version>
    <title>
        <en>Crop Control Override</en>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
Description:
Crop Control Override is a per-save crop policy manager for Farming Simulator 25. It lets players control which crops are permitted for the player, which crops NPC farmers may plant, and whether NPC crop planting should be limited by field size.

The mod includes an editable FS25-style GUI, per-save XML rule files, NPC field validation, blocked NPC field reporting, and a guarded Apply / Force Apply workflow to prevent accidental invalid save states.

Main GUI features:
- ALL RULES: view and edit crop policy rules.
- DISABLED: view globally disabled crops.
- SIZE LIMITED: view crops with NPC field-size limits.
- NPC DISABLED: view crops NPCs should not plant.
- VALIDATION: view existing NPC fields that violate the active policy and use the guarded dry-run / confirm reset workflow.
- SUMMARY: view active config, rule counts, and validation state.
- HELP: view in-game guidance.

Configuration:
- APPLY / FORCE APPLY writes staged crop-rule changes to the active per-save XML.
- DISCARD resets staged values.
- SAVE DEFAULTS TO CONFIG.XML backs up the existing template config and writes the current full active rule set to config.xml.
- Existing per-save XML files are not overwritten by Save Defaults.
- RESET BLOCKED DRY-RUN does not change the save state. CONFIRM RESET performs the actual blocked-field reset after review.
- VALIDATION includes RESET MODE: CULTIVATED or RESEED SEASONAL.
- RESEED SEASONAL uses the current seasonal planting window and CCO policy rules to choose a replacement crop for blocked NPC fields.
- GRASS may be used as a lifecycle reseed candidate when seasonal and policy checks allow it.
- Reseed candidate weighting can be tuned in XML with reseedCandidateWeights using seasonalMission, seasonalLifecycle, and leaveCultivated weights.
- Weighted reseed can produce CULTIVATED_VARIETY, leaving some reset fields cultivated instead of reseeding them.

Changelog 2.0.1.9:
- Extended external l10n support across the CCO GUI, including labels, tabs, buttons, status text, help text, validation text, and runtime GUI notices.
- Added a larger Courseplay-style l10n key set so community translators can add complete GUI translations through l10n/l10n_*.xml files.

Changelog 2.0.1.8:
- Updated localisation to use Courseplay-style external l10n files loaded through filenamePrefix="l10n/l10n".
- Removed duplicated inline l10n entries from modDesc.xml so community translations can be added via l10n/l10n_*.xml files.

Changelog 2.0.1.7:
- Fixed the permission-hook installer load order so the admin-permission build loads cleanly before installing Farm Management admin listeners.

Changelog 2.0.1.6:
- Remote dedicated-server clients that elevate to game admin/master user through the Farm Management admin console can now unlock CCO editing for that session.
- Added a permission refresh handshake so admin status changes are sent to the server and the CCO GUI refreshes without using local client XML files.
- Server-side validation still protects rule changes; normal remote clients remain read-only.

Changelog 2.0.1.5:
- Added dedicated-server admin/master-user edit permissions using the EasyDevControls-style authority model.
- Remote server admins can edit CCO rules through server-validated multiplayer events while normal remote clients remain read-only.
- Dedicated-server clients still do not read, create, or write local CCO XML files.

Changelog 2.0.1.4:
- Fixed the custom CCO GUI opening path by removing the unstable paging selector that could trigger a TextElement stack overflow in some FS25 builds.
- Remote multiplayer clients now show a waiting/sync state instead of rendering local default rules before the server snapshot arrives.

Changelog 2.0.1.3:
- Fixed remote multiplayer client sync requests firing before the server connection is ready.

Changelog 2.0.1.2:
- Dedicated/cloud multiplayer clients now ignore local CCO XML files and use an in-memory ruleset synced from the server.
- Remote multiplayer clients are read-only by default, preventing local savegame XML creation or accidental rule writes.
- Single-player, local-host multiplayer, and server-side file behaviour remain unchanged.

Changelog 2.0.1.1:
- Fixed dedicated/cloud multiplayer client GUI refresh after server-side rule changes; the originating client now receives the server-authoritative update and refreshes an open CCO GUI.

Changelog 2.0.1.0:
- Added multiplayer event handling so GUI changes and server-side reset/apply actions are sent to the server on dedicated multiplayer games.
- Updated NPC crop planning to use FieldManager.generatePlannedFruitForField instead of the old mission-generation flag mutation.
- Added defensive error handling around NPC crop replacement during planned fruit generation.
- Moved localisation to external l10n files so additional languages can be added more easily.

Hotkeys:
ALT+C opens the Crop Control Override GUI. This keybind can be changed in the in-game controls menu.
Mouse: use the GUI tabs, table rows, and buttons.
Keyboard: use the displayed FS25 footer actions for tab navigation, Load Defaults, and back.

Useful console commands:
ccoGui, ccoStatus, ccoWhichConfig, ccoReload, ccoValidateSave, ccoScanBlocked, ccoResetBlocked dryrun, ccoResetBlocked, ccoListNpcCandidates, ccoSeasonProbe, ccoGrowthProbe, ccoHelp

GitHub link:
https://github.com/SimGamerJen/FS25_CropControlOverride
]]></en>
        <de><![CDATA[
Beschreibung:
Crop Control Override ist ein speicherstandbasiertes Fruchtarten-Regelwerk für Farming Simulator 25. Mit dem Mod kann festgelegt werden, welche Fruchtarten für Spieler erlaubt sind, welche Fruchtarten NPC-Landwirte anbauen dürfen und ob der NPC-Anbau durch eine maximale Feldgröße begrenzt werden soll.

Der Mod enthält eine bearbeitbare GUI im FS25-Stil, XML-Regeldateien pro Spielstand, Validierung von NPC-Feldern, Anzeige blockierter NPC-Felder sowie einen geschützten Anwenden-/Erzwingen-Ablauf, um unbeabsichtigte ungültige Spielstände zu vermeiden.

Wichtige GUI-Funktionen:
- ALLE REGELN: Fruchtarten-Regeln anzeigen und bearbeiten.
- DEAKTIVIERT: global deaktivierte Fruchtarten anzeigen.
- BEGRENZT: Fruchtarten mit NPC-Feldgrößenbegrenzung anzeigen.
- NPC DEAKTIVIERT: Fruchtarten anzeigen, die NPCs nicht anbauen sollen.
- VALIDIERUNG: bestehende NPC-Felder anzeigen, die gegen die aktive Regel verstoßen, und den geschützten Testlauf-/Bestätigungsablauf zum Zurücksetzen verwenden.
- ZUSAMMENFASSUNG: aktive Konfiguration, Regelanzahl und Validierungsstatus anzeigen.
- HILFE: Hinweise zur Bedienung im Spiel anzeigen.

Konfiguration:
- ANWENDEN / ERZWINGEN schreibt vorbereitete Änderungen an einer Fruchtarten-Regel in die aktive XML-Datei des aktuellen Spielstands.
- VERWERFEN setzt vorbereitete Werte zurück.
- STANDARD SPEICHERN IN CONFIG.XML erstellt zuerst eine Sicherung der bestehenden Vorlagenkonfiguration und schreibt anschließend den aktuellen vollständigen Regelsatz in config.xml.
- Bestehende XML-Dateien einzelner Spielstände werden durch Standard Speichern nicht überschrieben.
- RESET BLOCKED DRY-RUN ändert den Spielstand nicht. CONFIRM RESET führt das tatsächliche Zurücksetzen blockierter Felder nach der Prüfung aus.

Änderungen 2.0.1.9:
- Externe l10n-Unterstützung auf die CCO-GUI erweitert, einschließlich Beschriftungen, Reitern, Schaltflächen, Statustexten, Hilfetexten, Validierungstexten und GUI-Meldungen zur Laufzeit.
- Ein größerer l10n-Schlüsselsatz im Courseplay-Stil wurde hinzugefügt, damit Community-Übersetzer vollständige GUI-Übersetzungen über l10n/l10n_*.xml ergänzen können.

Änderungen 2.0.1.8:
- Lokalisierung auf Courseplay-ähnliche externe l10n-Dateien umgestellt, geladen über filenamePrefix="l10n/l10n".
- Doppelte Inline-l10n-Einträge aus modDesc.xml entfernt, damit Community-Übersetzungen über l10n/l10n_*.xml ergänzt werden können.

Änderungen 2.0.1.7:
- Die Lade-Reihenfolge des Berechtigungs-Hook-Installers korrigiert, damit der Admin-Berechtigungs-Build sauber lädt, bevor Listener für Farmverwaltungs-Administratoren installiert werden.

Änderungen 2.0.1.6:
- Entfernte Clients auf dedizierten Servern, die sich über die Farmverwaltung als Spieladministrator/Master User anmelden, können CCO-Bearbeitung nun für diese Sitzung freischalten.
- Eine Berechtigungsaktualisierung sendet Admin-Statusänderungen an den Server und aktualisiert die CCO-GUI, ohne lokale Client-XML-Dateien zu verwenden.
- Die serverseitige Validierung schützt Regeländerungen weiterhin; normale entfernte Clients bleiben schreibgeschützt.

Änderungen 2.0.1.5:
- Admin-/Master-User-Bearbeitungsrechte für dedizierte Server nach dem EasyDevControls-Berechtigungsmodell hinzugefügt.
- Entfernte Serveradministratoren können CCO-Regeln über serverseitig validierte Mehrspieler-Ereignisse bearbeiten, während normale entfernte Clients schreibgeschützt bleiben.
- Clients auf dedizierten Servern lesen, erstellen oder schreiben weiterhin keine lokalen CCO-XML-Dateien.

Änderungen 2.0.1.4:
- Korrigiert den CCO-GUI-Start, indem der instabile Seitenwahlschalter entfernt wurde, der in manchen FS25-Versionen einen TextElement-Stack-Overflow auslösen konnte.
- Entfernte Mehrspieler-Clients zeigen nun einen Warte-/Synchronisationsstatus, statt lokale Standardregeln vor dem Server-Snapshot darzustellen.

Änderungen 2.0.1.3:
- Synchronisationsanfragen entfernter Multiplayer-Clients werden nun erst gesendet, wenn die Serververbindung bereit ist.

Änderungen 2.0.1.2:
- Clients im dedizierten/Cloud-Multiplayer ignorieren lokale CCO-XML-Dateien und verwenden einen vom Server synchronisierten Regelsatz im Speicher.
- Entfernte Multiplayer-Clients sind standardmäßig schreibgeschützt, wodurch lokale savegame-XML-Erstellung und unbeabsichtigte Regeländerungen verhindert werden.
- Einzelspieler-, lokaler Host-Multiplayer- und serverseitiges Dateiverhalten bleiben unverändert.

Änderungen 2.0.1.1:
- Client-GUI-Aktualisierung im dedizierten/Cloud-Multiplayer nach serverseitigen Regeländerungen korrigiert; der auslösende Client erhält nun die serverseitige Aktualisierung und aktualisiert eine geöffnete CCO-GUI.

Änderungen 2.0.1.0:
- Multiplayer-Ereignisverarbeitung hinzugefügt, damit GUI-Änderungen und serverseitige Zurücksetzen-/Anwenden-Aktionen in dedizierten Multiplayer-Spielen an den Server gesendet werden.
- Die NPC-Fruchtplanung verwendet nun FieldManager.generatePlannedFruitForField anstelle der bisherigen Änderung von Missions-Flags.
- Defensive Fehlerbehandlung für die NPC-Ersatzfruchtwahl hinzugefügt.
- Lokalisierung in externe l10n-Dateien verschoben, damit weitere Sprachen einfacher ergänzt werden können.

Tastenkombinationen:
ALT+C öffnet die Crop Control Override GUI. Diese Tastenkombination kann im Steuerungsmenü des Spiels geändert werden.
Maus: GUI-Reiter, Tabellenzeilen und Schaltflächen verwenden.
Tastatur: die angezeigten FS25-Fußleistenaktionen für Reiterwechsel, Standardwerte laden und Zurück verwenden.

Nützliche Konsolenbefehle:
ccoGui, ccoStatus, ccoWhichConfig, ccoReload, ccoValidateSave, ccoScanBlocked, ccoResetBlocked dryrun, ccoResetBlocked, ccoListNpcCandidates, ccoSeasonProbe, ccoGrowthProbe, ccoHelp

GitHub-Link:
https://github.com/SimGamerJen/FS25_CropControlOverride
]]></de>
        <fr><![CDATA[
Description :
Crop Control Override est un gestionnaire de règles de cultures par sauvegarde pour Farming Simulator 25. Il permet de contrôler quelles cultures sont autorisées pour le joueur, quelles cultures les agriculteurs PNJ peuvent semer, et si les cultures PNJ doivent être limitées par taille de champ.

Le mod inclut une interface modifiable de style FS25, des fichiers XML de règles par sauvegarde, une validation des champs PNJ, un affichage des champs PNJ bloqués, ainsi qu’un flux sécurisé Appliquer / Forcer l’application pour éviter les états de sauvegarde invalides accidentels.

Fonctions principales de l’interface :
- TOUTES LES RÈGLES : afficher et modifier les règles de cultures.
- DÉSACTIVÉES : afficher les cultures désactivées globalement.
- LIMITÉES : afficher les cultures avec une limite de taille de champ PNJ.
- PNJ DÉSACTIVÉ : afficher les cultures que les PNJ ne doivent pas semer.
- VALIDATION : afficher les champs PNJ existants qui ne respectent pas la règle active et utiliser le flux sécurisé d’essai / confirmation de réinitialisation.
- RÉSUMÉ : afficher la configuration active, le nombre de règles et l’état de validation.
- AIDE : afficher l’aide intégrée.

Configuration :
- APPLIQUER / FORCER L’APPLICATION écrit les changements préparés d’une règle de culture dans le XML actif de la sauvegarde.
- ANNULER réinitialise les valeurs préparées.
- ENREGISTRER LES VALEURS PAR DÉFAUT DANS CONFIG.XML sauvegarde d’abord la configuration modèle existante, puis écrit l’ensemble complet des règles actives dans config.xml.
- Les fichiers XML des sauvegardes existantes ne sont pas écrasés par cette action.
- RESET BLOCKED DRY-RUN ne modifie pas la sauvegarde. CONFIRM RESET effectue la réinitialisation réelle des champs bloqués après vérification.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.9 :
- Extension de la prise en charge l10n externe à l’ensemble de l’interface CCO, y compris les libellés, onglets, boutons, textes d’état, textes d’aide, textes de validation et messages d’interface générés à l’exécution.
- Ajout d’un ensemble plus complet de clés l10n de style Courseplay afin que les traducteurs communautaires puissent ajouter des traductions complètes de l’interface via l10n/l10n_*.xml.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.8 :
- Mise à jour de la localisation pour utiliser des fichiers l10n externes de style Courseplay, chargés via filenamePrefix="l10n/l10n".
- Suppression des entrées l10n en double dans modDesc.xml afin que les traductions communautaires puissent être ajoutées via l10n/l10n_*.xml.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.7 :
- Correction de l’ordre de chargement de l’installation des hooks de permissions afin que la version avec permissions administrateur se charge correctement avant d’installer les écouteurs d’administration de la gestion de ferme.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.6 :
- Les clients distants d’un serveur dédié qui élèvent leurs droits en administrateur/master user via la gestion de ferme peuvent désormais déverrouiller l’édition CCO pour la session.
- Ajout d’une actualisation des permissions afin d’envoyer les changements de statut administrateur au serveur et de rafraîchir l’interface CCO sans utiliser de fichiers XML locaux côté client.
- La validation côté serveur protège toujours les changements de règles ; les clients distants normaux restent en lecture seule.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.5 :
- Ajout de la détection des droits d’édition administrateur/master user sur serveur dédié, inspirée du modèle de permissions d’EasyDevControls.
- Les administrateurs distants du serveur peuvent désormais modifier les règles CCO via des événements multijoueurs validés par le serveur, tandis que les clients distants normaux restent en lecture seule.
- Les clients dédiés ne lisent, ne créent et n’écrivent toujours aucun fichier XML CCO local.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.4 :
- Correction de l’ouverture de l’interface CCO en supprimant le sélecteur de pages instable qui pouvait provoquer un dépassement de pile TextElement dans certaines versions de FS25.
- Les clients multijoueurs distants affichent désormais un état d’attente/synchronisation au lieu d’afficher les règles locales par défaut avant la réception de l’instantané serveur.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.3 :
- Correction des demandes de synchronisation des clients multijoueurs distants déclenchées avant que la connexion serveur soit prête.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.2 :
- Les clients en multijoueur dédié/cloud ignorent désormais les fichiers XML CCO locaux et utilisent un jeu de règles en mémoire synchronisé depuis le serveur.
- Les clients multijoueurs distants sont en lecture seule par défaut, empêchant la création de XML savegame locaux ou les écritures de règles accidentelles.
- Le comportement fichier en solo, hôte multijoueur local et côté serveur reste inchangé.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.1 :
- Correction de l’actualisation de l’interface client en multijoueur dédié/cloud après les changements de règles côté serveur ; le client à l’origine de la demande reçoit désormais la mise à jour serveur et actualise l’interface CCO ouverte.

Journal des modifications 2.0.1.0 :
- Ajout de la gestion des événements multijoueur afin que les changements de l’interface et les actions serveur d’application/réinitialisation soient envoyés au serveur dans les parties multijoueur dédiées.
- La planification des cultures PNJ utilise désormais FieldManager.generatePlannedFruitForField au lieu de modifier temporairement les indicateurs de missions.
- Ajout d’une gestion défensive des erreurs lors du choix d’une culture PNJ de remplacement.
- Déplacement de la localisation vers des fichiers l10n externes afin de faciliter l’ajout d’autres langues.

Raccourcis :
ALT+C ouvre l’interface Crop Control Override. Ce raccourci peut être modifié dans le menu des commandes du jeu.
Souris : utiliser les onglets, les lignes du tableau et les boutons de l’interface.
Clavier : utiliser les actions affichées dans la barre inférieure FS25 pour changer d’onglet, charger les valeurs par défaut et revenir en arrière.

Commandes console utiles :
ccoGui, ccoStatus, ccoWhichConfig, ccoReload, ccoValidateSave, ccoScanBlocked, ccoResetBlocked dryrun, ccoResetBlocked, ccoListNpcCandidates, ccoSeasonProbe, ccoGrowthProbe, ccoHelp

Lien GitHub :
https://github.com/SimGamerJen/FS25_CropControlOverride
]]></fr>
    </description>

    <l10n filenamePrefix="l10n/l10n" />
    <iconFilename>icon_CropControlOverride.dds</iconFilename>
    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="CCO_OPEN_GUI">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lalt KEY_c"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>

    <actions>
        <action name="CCO_OPEN_GUI" axisType="HALF"/>
    </actions>

    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/Debug.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/CropControlOverrideChangeSettingsEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/CropControlOverrideMenu.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/CropControlOverride.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
</modDesc>
