<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modDesc descVersion="100">
    <author>SimGamerJen, Hyper138</author>
    <version>2.0.0-alpha.49</version>
    <title>
        <en>Crop Control Override</en>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
Description:
Crop Control Override is a per-save crop policy mod for Farming Simulator 25. It can disable selected fruit types, remove them from supported crop UI lists, prevent them from being used for NPC field jobs, and restrict NPC crop planting by field size. This merged build credits SimGamerJen and Hyper138, combining CropControlOverride with Hyper138's NPC crop-control and field-size governance concept.

This alpha rebuild combines the original CropControlOverride concept with NPC crop-size control and manual NPC field correction. Existing pre-2.0.0 / v1 config files using fruit entries with name/enabled attributes are automatically normalized into the new v2 format, while preserving custom and currently undiscovered crop rules. The new v2 config adds npcAllowed, npcMaxHa, and resetNpcFields attributes.

Hotkeys / GUI shortcuts:
Default hotkey: ALT+C opens the read-only CCO GUI. The GUI can also be opened with ccoGui. Views are selected using FS25-style tabs across the top of the screen. Reload and Back use the native bottom dialog button row. Help is available via the top-right ? button.

Useful console commands:
ccoHelp [rules|scan|reset|debug] - Show command help.
ccoStatus - Show version, active config, rule counts, and validation summary.
ccoGui [status|rules|disabled|limited|blocked|undiscovered|help] - Open the read-only custom GUI dashboard.
ccoWhichConfig - Show the active config path.
ccoReload - Reload the active XML config and reapply rules.
ccoListRules [CROP] - List crop policy rules.
ccoListConfigured [CROP] - List all configured rules, including undiscovered crops.
ccoListUndiscovered - List configured crops not present on the active map/save.
ccoNormalizeConfig [dryrun] - Migrate/normalize the active config to v2 format.
ccoSetCrop <CROP> <enabled> [npcAllowed] [npcMaxHa] - Update a rule in-game.
ccoExplain <CROP> - Show rule, discovery, and fruitType flag state.
ccoListFlags [CROP] - Show current fruitType flags.
ccoFindFruit <text> - Find fruitType names.
ccoScanFields [CROP] - Scan fields for invalid NPC crop/field-size combinations.
ccoScanBlocked [CROP] - List only blocked NPC fields.
ccoScanSummary [CROP] - Show a compact crop-by-crop field summary.
ccoValidateSave - Validate that no NPC fields violate active CCO rules.
ccoListLimited - List crops with active NPC field-size limits.
ccoListNpcCandidates <FIELD_ID> - List valid/blocked NPC crop candidates for a field.
ccoListDisabled - List crops disabled by CCO rules.
ccoListBlockedRules - List crops disabled or explicitly blocked for NPCs by CCO rules.
ccoResetNpcFields [CROP|all] [dryrun] - Set offending NPC fields to cultivated state.
ccoResetBlocked [dryrun] - Reset all currently blocked NPC fields.
ccoDebug on|off|toggle and ccoLogLevel DEBUG|INFO|WARN|ERROR - Control CCO logging. Detailed NPC replacement/block traces are DEBUG-level. ccoGuiTest opens a minimal dialog rendering test.

Startup validation:
On map load, CCO prints a one-line validation notice. If blocked NPC fields are found, use ccoScanBlocked and ccoResetBlocked dryrun before making changes.

Config location:
<UserDocuments>/My Games/FarmingSimulator2025/modSettings/FS25_CropControlOverride/config.xml
Per-save configs are stored under:
<UserDocuments>/My Games/FarmingSimulator2025/modSettings/FS25_CropControlOverride/saves/savegameX.xml

Alpha.38 notes:
This RedTape-style tabbed GUI foundation build keeps the validated alpha.7/alpha.8 field reset and NPC crop replacement logic intact. It retains alpha.9 legacy config migration, custom crop discovery, and undiscovered-rule preservation. Alpha.34 keeps the dedicated GIANTS GUI screen and FS25-style SmoothList rule table. Help is now a small clickable question-mark button in the top-right of the screen, leaving BACK as the only ESC/back-style footer action. Detailed NPC replacement/block traces remain DEBUG-level to reduce normal log noise.

Field reset safety:
ccoResetNpcFields and ccoResetBlocked only target NPC-owned fields and only crops that violate the configured rule. They are intended for cleaning up already-generated savegames after changing crop policy. Use dryrun first when testing.
        ]]></en>
    </description>
    <iconFilename>CropControlOverride.dds</iconFilename>
    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="CCO_OPEN_GUI">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lalt KEY_c"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>

    <actions>
        <action name="CCO_OPEN_GUI" axisType="HALF"/>
    </actions>

    <multiplayer supported="true"/>
    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/Debug.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/CropControlOverrideMenu.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/CropControlOverride.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
</modDesc>
